Arvind Kumar

Gurgaon, Haryana, India



stdntlfe@gmail.com



9792979142



linkedin.com/in/stdntlfe

Summary

Hi. I am a data scientist. I am very familiar to Deep learning apis such as Tensorflow, TensorflowLite, TfLearn, keras, pytorch, and fastai, mxnet. I have a good hands on working with Advanced R and Python and BI tools and technologies, AI, Big Data. I have quite a good knowledge of DL/ML Algorithm, have also developed Dashboards and Web Applications using flask/django. My area of expertise is building Image Processing, Speech Recognition and building models for food, healthcare and telecom sector, Classification/Prediction/Clustering, NLP and Chatbots. I usual using many technique and library, frameworks such as tensorflow, tesseract, machine learning such as CNN, DNN, FCRN, SVN etc. and I am generally attached to programming language in working. (r programming, pytorch ,opency, nlp, computer vision, Linux, Python, ,) Specifically, I have worked for long on machine learning and Deep learning including computer Vision and natural language processing and model building for the same. I understand the project requirement and will deliver the desired product within the time specified. I am an individual contractor, not an agency.

contact for machine learning final year capstone project's in B.Tech, M.Tech, PhD, M S

Experience



Mercki Data Science Specialist

Meraki Training Solutions

Apr 2023 - Present (3 months)

Working on Various Deep Learning Algorithms in Healthcare Department of Medongo and Axiphyl. Natural Language Processing - Audio Data Analysis. Audio Data Preprocessing, Changing Sampling rate using python.

Speech To Text - Working on Transformers Bert models from hugging face pretrained models. done with the Marathi Speech to text using transformers models, Hindi speech to text using transformers models. English speech to text using Facebook transformers models, multilingual speech to text using Facebook meta AI wav2vec2 models and newly created models like mms (Massively Multilingual Speech).

deployed all these models using FastApi.

Video Data Analysis - Working on various projects like -Face Recognitions, Face Matching from the database, Emotion Recognitions, Gender Classifications, Age Classifications using Tensorflow and Pytorch and converting them tflite and mobile torch for using in mobile flutter applications.



Professional Freelance Data Scientist

Afcodex Pvt Ltd

Aug 2020 - Jun 2023 (2 years 11 months)

Hi. I am a data scientist. I am very familiar to Deep learning apis such as Tensorflow, TensorflowLite, TfLearn, keras, pytorch, and fastai, mxnet. I have a good hands on working with Advanced R and Python and BI tools and technologies, AI, Big Data. I have quite a good knowledge of DL/ML Algorithm, have also developed Dashboards and Web Applications using flask/django. My area of expertise is building Image Processing, Speech Recognition and building models for food, healthcare and telecom sector, Classification/Prediction/Clustering, NLP and Chatbots. I usual using many technique and library, frameworks such as tensorflow, tesseract, machine learning such as CNN, DNN, FCRN, SVN etc. and I am generally attached to programming language in working.(r programming, pytorch ,opency, nlp, computer vision, Linux, Python, ,) Specifically, I have worked for long on machine learning and Deep learning including computer Vision and natural language processing and model building for the same. I understand the project requirement and will deliver the desired product within the time specified. I am an individual contractor, not an agency. I think i am aware of your project in detail.

Data Science Engineer

Dew Solutions Pvt Ltd

Jul 2019 - Aug 2020 (1 year 2 months)

Working as a part of Data Science team worked on doubt searching engine using python in which

data from images and process that in text using pytesseract library, performed data cleaning techniques like

stopwords removal etc. learnt about deployment of machine learning model using flask.

• building chatbot from scratch using spacy and rasa nlu trainer. we also used data for prediction from scrap

the website using beautifulsoup and built a bot on the basis of that our bot is more flexible can work for multiple clients at the same type without making any changes in the coding part just need to add some training data and chatbot will response whatever output you desire for your company.

 worked on multiple object detection using yolov3 and content based image retrieval system using opency.

Software Engineer Intern

Azure Power

Apr 2019 - Jul 2019 (4 months)

6 Data Scientist Professional Course & curriculum

edWisor.com

Dec 2018 - Apr 2019 (5 months)

Have undergone training in data science which includes data exploration, data cleaning and building predictive models using machine learning. Training also included projects on real-life data sets which were reviewed by Data Science experts. All the projects can be found at the link below:

https://github.com/stdntlfe

Education



Lovely Professional University

Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Computer Science 2015 - 2019 specialisation in Data science

Licenses & Certifications

Data Science Foundations - Level 1 - IBM

53b3fbf0-bca3-4757-84a4-1f6a0874c8e6

Data Science Foundations - Level 2 - IBM

fed5d22b-56fb-487e-a498-35a7668b2d47

Data Scientist with R Track - DataCamp 8740d8de60e32102165fa0c67f17733c1b068988

Data Scientist with Python Track - DataCamp

6e30619e3fc273fff52215c556c71ca23c91f3f4

Python for Data Science - IBM

baf7e925-8895-4600-8d7a-fb2d5c2dcd2a

Data Analysis with Python - IBM

9ed19384f3344cd2832fd6f6a763bea6

Data Visualization with Python - IBM

eb28f016ac9c443db24bdc2df4b837b4

Applied Data Science with Python - Level 2 - IBM

1e240eca-ea74-4609-a5fc-cc5fa7015c81

Deep Learning Fundamentals - IBM

57ed6133e73c4d07aefe6c73acd7e233

Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals - Coursera DDBQLFHPWS77

Leveraging Unstructured Data with Cloud Dataproc on Google Cloud Platform -

Coursera

PS8V3PRZWLZA

CutShort Certified Machine Learning (ML) - Basic - Cutshort 46185

CutShort Certified Python - Advanced - Cutshort 46190

Skills

Transformers • BERT (Language Model) • Speech Recognition • Facial Recognition • OpenCV • Flask • Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources (FHIR) • PyTorch • Machine Learning • Deep Learning